张咏轩的异想世界
时间轴：张咏轩 校正：张咏轩
新浪微博：@张咏轩
What is love If it's not with you
I know when you're alone you feel it too
In your arms is where I long to be
Cause being with you gives me sanity
oh...Listen to me darling
I wake up every morning Thinking bout the way you feel
I wonder if you know it
And what good is the party If you're not around
Listen to me now
What good is love
If it's not your love
It's a crazy party Im so glad to be with everybody
Balance Shake your body down to zhe ground
Me?
What's a song If you can't heart it too
Can't imagine dancing without Jewel
A shooting star, ain't really nothing to see
In the brighest night, be nice to me
oh....Listen to me darling
I wake up every morning Thinking bout the way you feel
I wonder if you know it And what good is the party
If you're not around Listen to me now
What good is love
If it's not your love
明尼苏达州来的鸟还有自己的舞步
For a bird from Minnesota you've got own moves
这不是舞步 这是事故
Oh actually that's wasn't a move,that was an acident.
不过我接受你的恭维
But I'll take the compliment.
多亏拉斐尔能帮我们照顾孩子
Glad Rafael is watch the kids.
是啊，这样今天你得和我在一起..一整晚
Yes and it Looks like you're stuck with me...all night.
你是我的唯一 布鲁
You are one of my only Blu.
那太好了，因为公的就剩我一个了（...汗!!!）
Ah,that's a good thing, since I am be the only other one.
-比翼鸟 新年快乐 -拉斐尔 他们在哪？
- Hi, lovebirds, happy new year! - Rafa, where are...
孩子们和路易兹在一起 不用担心！
The kids are with Luiz.dont worry!
担心？我们很担心
Worries, right here.
-路易兹 孩子们呢？-什么？我又没有孩子
- Luiz, where are the kids? - What? I have no kids.
Jewel & blu - 我们的孩子
Our Kids!
-哦 对了 我交给小不点了 -小不点！
- oh right! I leave them with Tiny. -Tiny?
干嘛 她可是这里最棒的保姆
What? She is the excellent babysitter.
我是这里最差劲的保姆
I'm a horrible babysitter.
这一定会很炫的
This must be awesome!
行了 我已经计算过了
All right,I've done all the calculations
每次爆炸都会完美的踩在节奏点上
And each explosion will be pperfectly synced to the beat.
除非我没有算上这个...
Unless I didn't carry the one...
我觉得...这里会有红色 蓝色 绿色 黄色...紫色
Here's my vision...Red, blue, green, yellow, yellow... purple.
我觉得会是...
And it'my vision...
我觉得你们爸妈不会想看到这个的
I don't think your parents will like see that very much
那我们开始吧
Here we go.
-你这是要去哪儿啊小鸟    -这是什么？
- Where are you going, little birds? - What is it?
-爸爸   -你们知道规矩的
- Ah Dad! - Guys, You know the rules
没有大人的监督 不能放烟花
No pyrotechnics without adult supervision.
我们问过小不点了
We ask Tiny
这就更糟了 抱歉小不点
That's even worse. Sorry Tiny.
工钱我不要了 布鲁先生
You don't have to need pay me salary, Mr Blu.
下次玩 一定要先问我
Kids next time, ask me.
-可你每次都说不  -不 我没有
- But you always says no.  - No I don't.
-爸爸 你在否认现实
- Daddy, you're in denial.
-好吧 亲爱的 我经常说不嚒
Ok honey, did I always say no?
是的 哦 我是说...不...
yes! oh I mean...no.
太好了，现在妈妈也在说不了
Great, now Mom same too.
听着 我们是地球上最后的蓝斯皮克斯金刚鹦鹉
Listen, we are the last blue speakes Macaws left on this planet
我们得注意安全
We have to stay safe.
-有蓝色羽毛的鸟
- Birds with blue feathers...
-要团结在一起
-Have to stick together
我闻到烤鸡味了
I smell chicken.
啊 不不不....
No, no, no!
根据我的计算 这是他今天说的第27个不了
By my count he said "no" 27 times today.
-救命   -啊...
- Help! - What?
大家伙 快跑
Everybody fly!
这不公平 凭什么 只有爸爸玩的这么爽
Oh man! How can Dad gets time all the fun?
看啊 成功了
Look! It worked!
看来今年开了个好头
Well, this year has a great started.
里约大冒险 2
RIO 2
亚马逊之行 第七天
Amazon Expedition. 7th day.
距里约热内卢 2000英里
3200km from Rio
我们到达热带雨林的中心
We can reach the center of the rainforest.
当我们沿着河流毫不费力的向前划行的时候
We are surrounded by plants and animals struggling for survival.
周围都是挣扎生存的植物和动物
As we effortlessly guide down the river.
毫不费力的是你
Effortless for you.
哇哦 好漂亮
Wow! How pretty!
吐出来 快吐出来
Spit it out! Spit it out!
我们已经接近亚马逊树林鹌鹑的栖息地
We are nearly the nature ground of the Amazon uru-buck.
六个月前我们从走私者手中救下这只小鸟
6 months ago, we rescued this little bird form smugglers.
那时候它生着病，营养不良 还断了一条腿
It was sick, malnourished, with a broken leg.
而现在 我可靠的助手..
But now, my trusty assistant...
我是说我的妻子兼同事
I mean, loveing wife and colleague
就要把它放归回自然
will release it back to natural habitat.
都没事了 你可以走的 就像这样
It's okay, you can go now. Just like this.
还是让我跟他说吧
Let me talk to her.
走吧
Go on!
-你觉得他会没事吗   -给他一点时间
- Do you think she's gonna be okay? - Give her some time
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
等一下 它..好像在说什么 图里奥
Wait a minute. What she is saying, Tulio?
他是不舍得我们 在和我们说再见
It is just hard for her to say goodbye.
不 我觉得他好像在警告我们
No, I think is trying to warn us.
不不不 琳达 这可能是吸引异性的舞蹈
No,no,no, Linda,It may be some mating dance.
图里奥 看那 快划 快啊
Tulio, look! Paddle! now!
好的 好的
Okay, okay!
往右...不不不 往左
To the right ! No,no the left
往前 往前
Forward! Forward!
你想清楚再说 图里奥
Make up your mind, Tulio!
这下可糟了
Chese and sprinkles!
哦 不  快划快划 快点！
Oh no! Row, row! Faster!
琳达
Linda!
图里奥
Tulio
感谢上帝 你没有事
Thank heavens you're ok.
图里奥 这是..
Tulio, is that...
啊 琳达 真难以置信
Linda, this is incredible!
《Breakfast in Rio》
早上好 珠儿
Goodmornning, Jewel
嘿 你们看我找到了什么
Hey,everyone look what I found.
布鲁？
Blu ?
孩子们？
Kids?
大家都去哪儿了？
Where's everyone...
-好了 谁肚子饿了想吃早饭   -难以置信
Okay, who is ready to some Breakfast?  -Unbelievable.
你知道么 那些全麦煎饼
Did you know that this whole pancakes
所含的维生素矿物质是普通煎饼的两倍
has twice the vitamins and minerals?
而且加上蓝莓后味道会好上4倍
and with blueberries is 4 times to tasty.
嘿 蓝莓都哪去了
Hey Where are the blueberries?
爸爸 你在找这个吗
Oh Dad, looking for this?
给我吧
bring it!
已经到了最后关头 他的脚仿佛有魔力一样
In the final minutes, he has his magic in feet
他射门了
he shoots!
球进了！
- Goal!
噢耶 我接到了 我真是太棒了
Oh yeh, I got, I'm good.
爸爸 注意了
Hands up, Dad.
啊哦
Aho!
哦 帅呆了
Awesome!
嗨  妈妈
Hi, Mom!
-这下惨了  -该走了
- Busted. - Time to go.
亲爱的 你饿了吗
Hi, honey. Are you hungry?
布鲁 我跟你说过的
Blu, we talked about this.
是吗 我不记得了 哦 对的 你拿的是什么
Did we?Ummm,so,uhhh,so whatta you got there?
-早饭  -很好笑 不过  说真的 这是什么
- Breakfast. - That's funny, but Seriously what is that?
这是个巴西栗
It's a Brazil nut.
离城市这么近的地方居然也有
I never thought I'd find one this close to the city.
-我要教孩子们怎么打开  -你是说打开这个吗
- I want to show the kids how to open it. - I mean, so?
爸爸已经教过我们了
Daddy already shown us.
等等 来了
Wait  back.
爸爸妈妈 你们上电视了
Mom  Dad  you're on TV.
巴西鸟类学家图里奥蒙泰罗博士
Doctor Tulio Monteiro,the"birdman"of Brazial
今天宣布了一项重大发现
announced a major discovery today
我们相信 我们在亚马逊丛林深处找到了野生的
We believe we having encountered a wild blue speakes macaw
蓝色金刚鹦鹉
in Amazon jungle
蓝色金刚鹦鹉之前被认为在野外全部灭绝了
The blue speakes Macaw was thought practically extinct
仅存的一家鹦鹉
With the last remain family
目前居住在里约的布鲁鸟类保护区
living under the protection at the "blu" bird's shrine In Rio de Janeiro
我们出名了
We are famous .
如果找到这些野生鹦鹉 他们的家园将受到保护
If these birds can be found  their home will be saved
那里可能有很多这种鹦鹉
There may be the whole flock of birds there
如果真的有 我们会找到他们 并保护他们
If here is, we'll find them and protect them
你好 布鲁
Hi, Blu!
你好 琳达
Hi, Linda!
我们不是唯一的
We are not the only ones.
我们还有活着的同类啊
There are more of us there.
-是啊 太好了 -这么长时间 我一直...
- Yes, that's great.  - All this time I thought...
我一直以为...我们是孤独的
I thought we were alone.
嘿 以前也没有那么糟糕
This was not bad?
是挺好的 可是...
Of course not, but...
想象一下 有一大群同类
Imagine there was a whole flock of us.
那该有多么美妙啊
How amazing will that being!
-我们得做点什么   -真的吗
- We have to do something.  - We do?
对 我们去亚马逊
Yes, we have to fly to Amazon
去帮助琳达和图里奥找到他们
And help Linda and Tulio find them.
哦...我们不能说走就走
Wow...We can't just pack up and go.
为什么不能 现在正是时候出去让翅膀吹吹风了
Why not? It's time this family feel the wind in their wings.
看看我们 音乐播放器 电视 煎饼
Look at us! IPod television pancakes?
亲爱的 我们不是人类 我们可是鸟
We are not people, we are birds!
我们应该回到野外 做真正的鸟 布鲁
We have get out to the wild and be birds, Blu.
让孩子们回到大自然吧
Let the kids know their roots
看看我们从前的生活
Show them what I had.
他们需要这样 我们也需要
They need this we need this.
来吧，布鲁！你说呢？
Come on Blu! What do you say?
我不知道...也许吧...
I do not know. Maybe, but...
他没有说不
He didn't say no.
这就意味着他说 行
That's mean he probabiliy said yes.
-嘿 等一下   -亲爱的，一定会很好玩！
- What, no!  - It will be so much fun!
耶...我们要去亚马逊咯
We are come to the Amazon.
等一下，亚马逊是什么？
Wait, what is the Amazon?
亚马逊，目前世界上最濒危的生态系统之一
The Amazon is one of the most danger ecosystems
由于非法砍伐和耕种
Due to illegal deforestation and framing
我们希望博士和他的团队
Let's hope the dr.Monteiro and his team
能找到那些珍惜鸟类，让他们的家园得以保存
find these rare birds so their home can be save
那里可能有很多这种鹦鹉
There may be the whole flockout of there
如果真的有，我们会找到它们并保护他们
If there is, we'll find them and protect them
Ecochatos 把我的船准备好
Ecochatos. get my boat ready.
我要亲自去处理这件事情
I need to do this  personally.
下一个
Next
轮到我了，行了你们可以回家了
It's time for me, everybody can go home now.
你们正在看着的下一位，狂欢之王
You are looking for the next King of Carnival.
嘿 大鸟 祝你好运
Hi,big bird, good luck!
走路小心点，别躺着进去！
Whach out buddy!
棒极了！
Bravo!
棒极了！你唱的真是太好了
Bravo! That was amazing!
我亲爱的，你刚才一个音符也没落下
Eva, darling, you hit every note.
-伙计们？  -对！是的！
-Huh guys?  -Yeah yeah
还多了很多我从来没听过的音
In various a lot of notes I've ever heard of.
-拉斐尔  -别 别担心
- Rafa! - Do not worry!
我会和他们说的
I'll talk to them.
我会为你找到完美的角色！
We will find a perfect part for you!
嗯...潜规则也没用
Antarctica maybe.
最好如此 回头见
You bet! Bye bye!
再见 孩子们！
Goodbye, boys!
我们家里见，我的美味小芒果
See you back at home, my tasty mango!
哎...这些表演一点都不好 我连一点灵感都没有
None of the acts are inspiring.I am just not inspired!
狂欢节眼看就要到了
The carnival is right on the corner.
我们的名声会毁于一旦的
And our reputations are on the line.
明白！我们需要一些能让我们嗨起来的节奏
Copy yeat! we need something make us wild
我们需要 动感 火爆 激情
Something like jungle. We need something pop...
你知道激情怎么说么？
You know  pop is that word?
啪...下一个...
- Pop  - Next.
-布鲁  -对不起兄弟
- Blu!  - Sorry, man!
没关系 路易兹 我也很高兴见到你
It's Okay, Luiz! Good to see you too!
听着 布鲁 我们在寻找一位歌手
Listen, Blu, we are looking for a singer
一个舞者 样样都会的
a dancer, the whole package.
不要唱歌跑调 跳舞摔跤的 你懂我的意思么？
Yeah and you're more of a mumbler-shuffer.you catch my drift?
我不是来面试的
No I'm not here for the audition.
我有事情要宣布
I got news!
我准备要去亚马逊了
I'm going to the Amazon.
亚马逊
Amazon!
那可真够野的
That's wild.
是呀 珠儿觉得这对我们有好处
Yes, Jewel think will be good for us.
-有多野  -超级宇宙无敌野
- How wild?  - Real wild.
那里的蚊子能够一口吸干你的
There mosquitoes suck your blood like slurpess.
那里的蛇能一口将你整个吞下去
There snakes that swallow you whole.
那里还有吃肉的食人鱼 会吃肉的！
There carnivorous piranhas... eat fresh
哦！好极了 真不赖
Great,sounds pretty nice!
-我不去了   -得了伙计们
- I will not going! -Gus guys guys!
布鲁 你根本不用担心这些
Blu, you have nothing to worry about.
他们说的这些都有点夸张的过分了
All those stories are highly exaggerated.
-你真的这么想？  -当然了！
- You think so?  - Of course!
如果这对珠儿很重要 那你就去吧
If it is important to Jewel, Just do it.
老婆开心 日子舒心...
Happy wife happy life...
-一定要记住   -好的 对!
- Remember that.  - Okay, you're right.
你说的对 就当全家一起去度假 一定很有趣
You know,a little family vacation, might actually be fun.
再说了 又不是定居在那里
Plus it's not like it's foever!
这就对了
That's the spirit.
好的 谢谢伙计们！
Okay, thanks guys!
过段时间见
See you in a couple of weeks.
-一路顺风 布鲁   -记得带纪念品回来
- Safe treavles Blu!  - Bring me back a souvenir!
得了 他不会回来了
Dog, he can't come back.
他一定会挂在那里的
He's end...there.
亚马逊！
Amazon!
我们走 快点爸爸 快点
Let's go! Come on  Dad! come on!
好的 驱虫剂 净水剂 还有创可贴
Ok, bug spray check, water purifier cheak, Band-aids...
哦 我好像忘了点什么
I feel like I'm forgetting something.
哇哦 酷 是多功能瑞士军刀
Wow! Cool, the all-in-one Adventurer's knife.
-这个交给我来弄吧 -这不是给你准备的
-I'll be in charge of this. -That's not for you!
嘿 爸爸 来看我这个
Dad, look at this!
你知道亚马逊的蛇能一口把你吃掉吗？
Did you know the Amazon has snakes that can swallow you whole?
事实上这些故事写得太夸张了
Actually, Bia ,all those stories are highly exaggerated
不一定吧 你看这个
No, really! Look!
哦 这个好恶心啊
Oh..That's sick!
准备好出发了吗？
All right, Are we ready to go?
你带了个腰包？
A fanny pack?
是的 琳达给我的 用来装GPS定位
Yeah Linda gave it to me, I need it for the GPS.
哦 我的GPS呢
Where's the GPS.
卡拉 我们要走啦
Carla  we're leaveing.
我才不去呢！肯定很无聊
I'm not going! It's gonna be lame.
行了 找到了
OK, Here it is!
它有语音识别功能 很好用的 你看着
The voice recognition makes totally easier. Here watch this..
给我找琳达和图里奥
Finding Linda and Tulio.
正在搜索 去东京吃料理
Seaching for dining in Tokyo
好的 额 事实上这个还真不错
Ok,actually that is a nice suggestion.
-你相信这个女人？  -是的 我相信
- You trust this woman?  - Yes, I do.
嘿 等下伙计们 我们也要一起去
Wait us family, I will going too.
别担心哥们 我们会罩着你的
Do not worry buddy. We'll get you back.
-你老婆让你去了吗？  -当然！
- Eva let you come?  - Sure!
我答应她在狂欢演出里给他弄个角色
Promised her a place in the carnival show.
-答应他什么   -你们迟到了
- You did what?  -You guys are late.
-是有点晚  -但我们可是音乐家
-Clock late. - But musicians early.
等等 你们也要去吗？
Wait your guys are coming?
我们当然不会错过
We wouldn't miss it for the world.
我们要去丛林寻找最棒的歌手
We're gonna scout the wildest coolest talent in that jungle.
这是我们今年狂欢节演出的创作灵感
And it's our inspiration for the carnival show.
狂野的 亚马逊
Amazon untamed.
酷 我是说...好吧
Cool! I mean... Okay...
我也会去的
I guess I will go.
去亚马逊放手一搏
Amazon jungle for bust, baby!
都准备好去热带探险了么
Who's ready for a tropical adventure?
等等 等等 孩子们 还没有点名
Guys, wait up! We didn't do a head count! Hey guys wait up!
重新规划路线
Recalculating
嘿 小鸟 快回来
Hey Birds come back!
又是这样 丢下我自己走了！
They were go without me..again!
太让人伤心了！
This is Sadly!
《O Vida》
里约热内卢
欧鲁普雷图
巴西利亚
前方道路 拥堵
Heavy traffic ahead
多谢了 GPS小姐
Great..Thanks a lot GPS lady.
快点 快点 快点
Faster, faster!
慢点...
Slower...
我们到了孩子们，这里就是亚马逊的大门了
Here we are, kids! The gate way to the Amazon.
生存 还是....毁灭
"alive .." Or... Do not be!
这是个问题
That is the question!
究竟哪一个更高贵 去忍受这命运
Whether is nobler in the mind to suffer the slings
还是去忍受着无边的烦恼
And arrows of outrageous fortune
经受无边的摧残
Or to take arms against a sea of troubles
还是把它忘个干净
And by opposing end them
噢 真实太美妙了 奈杰尔 这是什么意思
Oh that's beautiful Nigel. What does it mean?
死亡 噶比
Death Gabi.
说的是死亡
Is about death.
哦 奈杰尔 我爱死你了
Oh Nigel, I love it when you get all dark and brooding.
嘿 笨鸟 该上场了
Hey bird, it's showtime!
我的观众正等着我呢
My audience waits!
从里约的丛林 到亚马逊的街头
From the streets of Rio to the Amazon jungle
有请 神秘的大鸟
The Bird of mystery.
别害羞，快来了解属于你的命运吧
Don't be shine learn your destiny
喂 别打蚂蚁的主意 干你的活去
Hey Get away form the ants. Back to work.
妈妈 我要玩这个 占卜
Mami, I want one, I want to furtune!
欢迎光临 夫人
Welcome, madam.
这只难以置信的鹦鹉 能够预示你的未来
This amazing Cockatoo reveal your future.
好了小鸟 选一个吧
All right bird.Take the furture.
快点 小鸟
Come on bird!
你干的很好 奈杰尔
You're doing right, Nigel.
快一点
Pick it up already.
加油 伙计们 就快到了 今天不用再飞了
Come on,almost there.No more flying today
晚一点 我们能赶上一艘船
We've got a boat to catch.
根据GPS的计算 明天一早我们就能到
According my friend here will get there by the morning.
他能活下来 但永远也飞不起来了
You will live but could never fly again
快点 小鸟 快给我算命
Come on!  My luck
-很好奈杰尔  -怎么要这么长时间
- You are very cute.- Why is it taking so long
我会这么惨 都是那只蓝色的鸟害的
That blue bird caused my misery
小鸟乖
Nice birddy.
为什么要打自己 为什么要打自己
Why are you hitting yourself? Why are you hitting yourself?
哇哦 奈杰尔好有男子汉气概
Wow..Nigel is very macho.
谢谢
Thank you.
我自由了
I'm free!
这里有只箭毒蛙
Poisonous frog!
嘎嘎叫的凤头鹦鹉 呐喊着要去复仇
The croaking cockatoo doth bellow  for revenge.
这是莎士比亚写得
That's Shakespeare, by the way.
-没有你的表演 他一文不值  -说得好
Without your interpretation it's nothing. -Good point.
一个完成旧任务的好时机
哦 这空气 又清新 又舒适
Oh this air is so fresh and full
再见了 城市里的雾霾
Goodbye, smelly city air!
对！再见！
Yes, goodbye.
嘿 谢谢你能为我这样做 真的很谢谢你
Hey Thank you for doing this. I really appreciate.
为了你 我愿意做任何事情
I would do anything for you.
-你懂得 对么？  -我当然懂
- You know that, right? - Of course I know.
我们不是来这吃点心的 我们是来复仇的
We aren't here for neck, We are here to revenge.
等乘客都睡着的时候
When these pesky passengers flat sleep
我们就好好关爱下我的蓝色朋友们
We'll show our blue friends some love
给他们一点...毒爱
Some poisonously love.
哦 这个我最拿手了
Oh..That is my specialty.
我们在午夜发动攻击 这样显得更加邪恶
We will attack at midnight hour because it is more evil.
保持警惕
Stay alert.
午夜！袭击的时间
Midnight. Time to attack!
奈杰尔 奈杰尔
Nigel. Nigel.
看看我们两个另类的生物
Look for us mistys.
一只剧毒的青蛙 一只不会飞的怪鸟
A toxic frog and a flyless freak.
我们如此的不同 又如此的相同
So different and yet the same
亲爱的 当你睡着了 我们是朋友 那样很好
My darling whilesleep all is well We're friends and that's swell
可是有个秘密一定要告诉你....我爱你
But the truth I have a secret to tell...I love you
人们说这不对 很可笑 一只青蛙怎么和鸟恋爱
People says it is wrong and absurda frog and a bird love
《Poisonous Love》
可我心里知道 这是命中注定的
But I know in my heart this is ment to be
如果我们能拥抱亲吻 那真是天堂般的幸福
If only we could could hug and could kiss be in heavenly bliss
可你的肺会烂掉 就像这样
But your lungs would explode and you'd look just like this
你会窒息 脸涨成蓝色
As you'd hemorrhage and gag would cough up your face turn blue
哦...
Oh
不过亲爱的 我会照顾你
But darling I'll protect you
我会的 你尽管放松
Do not worry just chill
因为我能杀掉任何鸟 只要是为了你
Cause there isn't a bird that I wouldn't kill ..for you
你看不出来吗
Can't you see...
我们注定要在一起
oh we were destined to be
因为我们的爱
For we have love
有毒的爱...
Poisonous love
-爱...  -虽然 是的
-Love - Yes i know
是的
- Yes
我知道你没法拥抱我
I know that you can't hold me
投入我的怀抱吧
Feel me close now
你爱的翅膀 围绕着我
Your loving wings enfold me
命运告诉我 爱...
Fate told me..love..
有毒的爱...
Poisonous love...
站在这里
Standing here
你离我是如此的近 可是..
You're so near and..
-又那么远  -就像一颗星星
Yet so far..like a star
我们到了
Here we are
-哪儿？  -该怎么办？
- Where - What to do
哦
oh poo
你是我的罗密欧 我是你的朱丽叶
Your my romeo I'm juliet
我们天生一对 可是 如果我们触碰哪怕一点点
We are so perfect and yet if we touch not by much
可以确信一点
Still on all you can bet
那就是 永别
It's good bye
我会哭泣
And I'll cry
因为你已不再
As you die
死于我们有毒的...
From our poisonous...
爱...
Love...
好可怕的梦
What a nightmare.
查理 你应该把我叫醒的
Charli, you were supposed to wake me.
要行动了
It's time.
能做奈杰尔的搭档真好
I love being on team of Nigel.
我想不出什么比在夜晚下
I can not think of anything more romantic than
给乘客下毒更浪漫的事情了
poisoning passengers on a moonlight cruise
住手
Stop!
那家伙是我的
That one is mine.
一闪一闪小布鲁...找你找得好辛苦...
Twinkle, twinkle, little Bluey.How I wondered where were you?
高高的挂在天空中...
Up above the world so high.
今天让你..一命呜呼
Are you ready to die?
你应该吃块绿箭薄荷糖
You need one breath mint.
你睡着了都要嘲笑我！
Even you sleep you mock me?
等等我
Wait for me.
别丢下我
Do not leave me!
-迪耶戈 别到处乱跑  -我什么也没干啊
- Tiago, stop leaveing around. - I didn't do anything.
孩子 听你妈妈的话
Tiago Gunderson, listen to your mother.
哦 天
Oh man.
-我们快到了  -等一下伙计们
-We're almost there right. -Hey Guys wait up...
记住 有蓝色....算了
Remember... Birds have...never mind.
他们都跑了
They are getting away.
快醒醒 你这个吃蚂蚁的笨蛋 快跟上他们
Wake up, you ant-eating idiot. follow them!
好多了 现在给我快一点
Better! Now get to times faster!
这个笨蛋！
River hugs!
我一直在想 你是不是比猴子还笨
You! I always suspected that was dumber than a monkey.
现在我懂了
And now I know.
老板 您来丛林里干什么？
Boss, what are you doing in the jungle?
你应该问他们来这里干什么
Perhaps the better question is: What are they doing?
那些环保狂
Nature Freaks.
这里有几百万平方英里的丛林
Too million hectares of jungle
可替他们偏偏跑到这里来
And they play in my backyard?
我可不是好惹的家伙
I don't think so.
你也知道 朋友 我们的伐木作业
As you know my friends, these our operations
稍微有点....违法
is a bit... illegal.
如果这些人找到那些鸟 我们的生意就完了
If these two nuts found those birds, we have no business
所以你现在要尽快结束他们的寻鸟丛林探险
And that's why you must end their little bird watching expedition
找到他们 赶走他们
Find them! And get rid of them.
其余的人 都给我砍树去
The rest of you go cut some trees.
谁在乎一群什么破鸟
Who cares a bunch of birds?
鹦鹉会把鸟巢筑在巴西栗树附近
The macaws should be nesting near the Brazial nut trees
所以我觉得我们应该...
So..I think that we should continue with...
图里奥 你在听我说话吗
Tulio, are you listening to me?
你已到达目的地
You have arrived at your destination
看！是不是很管用 我们到了
You see? It worked like a charm. Here we are.
这是哪？
Where?
嗯 这东西稍微有点误差
Oh..These things have a margin of error.
我跟你说过别相信那个女人
I told you not trust that woman.
这是一个幼虫 他就要进入变蛹的阶段了
That's a Heliconius larva.it's about to enter the pupa state
哈 你说桶
Ha! You said poop
-你们跟紧了  -我要去找他们
-hey kids stay close. -I'll get them.
好吧 你们留在这里别动 我去周边看看
Okay, you stay here and I take a look around.
别担心 我们就在这 我们哪儿都不去
Do not worry, we'll be here.Not going anywhere.
-我后背的羽毛都竖起来了
--My feathers is poppin'up on the back ofmy neck.
-我可不喜欢这个感觉
- I don't like this.
我们掉头吧
Let's back it up.
比亚 迪耶戈
Bia? Tiago!
拜托 小姐 别让我失望
Come on lady don't let me down.
规划前往...秀场的路线
Calculating route to: funky town
好吧 太好了
Ok great
伙计们？
Ok guys...Guys?
呵呵 可以 这很好玩
Haha come on guys. Very funny.
很好 很好 很聪明的玩笑
Funny same. Very clever.
珠儿 你在哪？
Jewel where are you?
孩子们 老婆？
Kids? Jewel?
啊 蓝色金刚鹦鹉 琳达！
Ah it's a Macaw! Linda!
放开我
Let me go!
放开我 你这个野蛮人
Let me go! you barbarian.
布鲁？
Blu?
我发誓 这声音听起来像布鲁的
I swear that's sound like my Blu.
不 不可能 琳达
That's impossible, Linda.
他在家里 既舒适又安全
He is home in Rio safe and sound.
我可是美国公民 你这个野蛮人
I am an americian citizen, you savage!
我要求见美国大使 我知道我有这个权利
I demand to see my ambassador.I know my rights.
我有这个权利
I know my rights.
退后 野蛮人
Back up barbarian.
对 没错 这是个勺子 也是个叉子
Yeah That's right.Is a spoon and a fork.
害怕了吧 怕的发抖了吧
Be afraid. Be very afraid.
啊哦...把你的东西放下
Aho my buddy put that spork down.
放开我...有种来啊
Let me go...leave me. Luckily I'm bigger.
真不敢相信 我们找到他们了
I can't believe we found them.
严格的说 是他们找到了我们
Well, technically they found us.
好吧 得找点东西来写名字
Ok we're going to need some name tags.
哦 那是绿箭薄荷糖
Oh hello em.. There are mints.
你用不到它 不过味道还不错...你可以试试
Don't you need it but they are good.you eat them.
不 别连盒都吞下去
No no no... not the whole box.
赶快..把它..吐出来
Get that out of your mouth
还记得第一部里珠儿还有布鲁么？
出什么事情 怎么了？
What is this doing here? What's going on?
我们发现他们飞得离人类太近
We found them flying too close to the humans.
什么 你是谁？
What? And who are you?
额 可不是一个合适的回答 我问你话呢
Er...This is not the appropriate answer.I asked a question.
你们到底从哪来
Where did you come from?
- 嘿 退后
-Hey back off
- 不好意思小姐...
-Excuse me young lady, is it...
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
这...这怎么可能
How... How did this...
伐木工来的时候到处都是大火
Some loggers came
到处都是浓烟 然后...
There was fire and.. so much smoke.
我把你藏在翅膀下面
I hide you under my wing.
然后你就...不见了
-And you were.. -Gone
我一直在找你
I was looking everywhere for you.
我在这
I'm here
爸爸
Daddy
爸爸？
Daddy?
我好想你
I missed you.
没事了 一切都过去了
It's Okay.It's Okay. Now...
有爸爸在
Dad has you.
看看你 我的小女儿
Look at you. It's my little girl.
已经长大了
Have grown up.
长得这么漂亮
So beautiful.
就像你的妈妈一样
Just like your mother.
对不起 我把你弄丢了
I'm so sorry I missed you.
我无法想象这些年你一个人到底怎么过来的
I can not imagine you were alone all this time.
没什么 爸爸 我不孤单
It's okay, Dad. I wasn't alone.
布鲁找到我了
Blu found me.
很高兴见到你 先生
Nice to meet you Sir.
把翅膀收起来 布鲁 到我这来
Cut down wings away Blu.Now come here.
-当然   -近一点
- Sure okay. - Closer.
-是吗？ -再近点
- Really? - Closer.
你把我女儿带回来了
You brought my jewell back to me.
我谢谢你
I thank you.
现在我要拥抱你
I'll hug you now.
额 好的
Em..Okay.
-行了 过来吧   -抱上了
- Come here. - Here we are.
真是我的荣幸
My pleasure.
什么 你在哭吗？
Nico, Are you crying?
看到这么感人的场面 我内心很脆弱啊
It's a heavy moment and I'm very vulnerable right now.
拥抱吧 我们
Let me give you an arm.
妈妈 你没事吧
Mom, are you okay?
妈妈？我当外公了
Mom ? I'm Grandpa.
我当外公了
I'm Grandpa.
看看 我是外公了
Look at me I'm a Grandpa!
爸爸 这是卡拉 比亚 迪耶戈
Daddy is this: Carla Bia and Tiago.
-你好呀 先生
- Nice to meet you, sir
-不要叫我先生 我的小姐
- There is no sir around here, my young lady.
-你应该叫我..帕帕
-You'll call me papa
-帕帕 哦 我喜欢
- Pa Pa? Oh I like that.
我是外公啦 太好啦  我是外公啦
I'm the papa papa. I'm papa papa.
别把外公弄伤了 孩子们
Kids, go easy on old grandpa
你还叫我先生
You call me sir.
我女儿回来啦
My daughter has returned.
这些年我们东躲西藏 人类把我们逼往
For years we live because humans fleeing push us
越来越深的丛林
deep into the jungle.
不过你看 我们找到了一个避难所
But as you can see we‘re found a sanctuary.
我们终于可以在这里扎根了
A place we can finally put down roots.
大伙们 出来吧
Everyone. Come on. All leave the nest.
我女儿回来啦
My daughter is home.
出来吧小鸟们  我的珠儿回来啦
Come birds. My Jewel is back.
珠儿？
Jewel?
让开  让开 珠儿！
Make way, make way. Jewel!
咪咪婶婶 咪咪婶婶
Aunt Mimi? Aunt Mimi!
哦 我想死你了
I felt you so much.
我的小野花终于回家了
My wild little flower has return.
我就知道你会回来
I knew you are coming back.
我会用鸟粪算命
I saw the specks of dropings.
看看这些小家伙们
Look at these puppies.
谁是可爱的小蓝皮克斯鹦鹉
Who's the most cutest little macaws?
哦 你长得可有点着急啊
Oh you look big for your age.
哦 咪咪婶 这是苏
Mimi  this is the Bilu.
事实上我叫布鲁
Actually I am the Blu.
-我们都是鹦鹉 呵呵   -我名字是Blu
- We are all - It's mean is my name.
金刚鹦鹉都是蓝色的
So that is why we call blue macaws.
你就依着她吧
Just go with it.
《Welcome Back》
原来你在这种鸟里长得算是挫的
So that's what a blue macaw is supposed to look like?
看她多耀眼
Look it shining
她的羽毛闪闪发光
Her feathers is glow
现在丛林都在欢笑
Now the jungle is smiling
因为我们的宝贝回来了
Because our baby is home.
你是否和我一样的感受
Can you feel what I feeled
因为这一天终于来到
That day has come last
我们心爱的珠珠回来了
Our precious Jade has returned
我要第一个唱出来 欢迎回来
I'll be the first to say welcome back
罗伯特....我
Roberto, I...
欢迎回来
Welcome back
我是说 欢迎 欢迎 欢迎 欢迎
I say welcome back welcome welcome...
回来...
Back...
-哇 你看上去棒极了   -你也是
- Wow..You look great. - So do you.
嗨 你好 我是珠儿的...重要的那一位
Hey, hi, hello. I am the Jewel significant other.
哦 那你就是那个俘获了珠珠芳心的幸运鸟
So you're the lucky bird who swept Ju-Ju of her feet, huh?
-珠珠？  -是啊
- Ju-Ju? - Yeah.
我们小时候一直给对方起可爱的小名
When we were kids we called cute name in each other.
是的 我叫他背头...呵呵
We did, I called him Beto.
那真可爱 我也喜欢起小名
That's adorable. I love doing nicknames.
你可从来没提起过什么罗伯特
You never mentioned any Roberto.
那是他没有什么可提的啊
There was nothing to mention.
嘿..我的搭档来了
Hey..There is my wing man.
有罗伯特放哨 我们都能安心睡觉了
We can rest with Rober to look out.
多亏艾迪教会我一切
Eduardo taught me everything I know.
-全靠你这只好鸟
- He is the bird.
-不 你才是好鸟...
-No.. You're the bird!
-不 你是只好鸟   -你才是好鸟...
-No, you're the bird.  -You're the bird
知道了 你们两个都是好鸟
We get it. You both are birds.
能不能别唧唧歪歪了 开始聚会吧
Now can we stop yapping and start party
《Beautiful Creatures》
哇哦...我记得这首歌
Oh well..I remember this song.
怎么可能忘记 它一直流淌在我们的血液里
How could you forget? It's in our blood baby.
这是只属于我们的歌
It's who we are.
不介意我借用她一会吧？嗯...
You don't mind if I borrow her for a minute, do you
-额 事实上我...   -来吧 珠珠 开始了
- Have you commented...- Come on, Ju-Ju let's go.
Let's come together  singing love and harmoni
We are so different  but the same inside our hearts
Beautiful colors  as far as the eyes can see ya
Open your wings  fly when you hear the call
Let's celebrate  calling the beautiful creatures
Come spread your wings dance and sing songs about freedom
Like lah lah lah hoo hoo
One for the jungle familia
Like bah bah bah boo boo
Calling the beautiful creatures
Come this way celebrate
Laugh and dance all the way
-这个地方真是潜力无穷啊  -我好喜欢他们这种歌
Follow me sing along
Lah lah bah bah boom boom...
Ja disse que Jade chegou
Ja disse que ja disse que Jade chegou...
Pop-pop  I am the pop-pop
I am the tchh I am your pop-pop
I am the pop-pop-pop  tchch pop-pop-pop
I am the pop-pop the tchhhchhc
Let's celebrate  calling the beautiful creatures
Come spread your wings  dance and sing songs about freedom
Like lah lah lah hoo hoo
One for the jungle familia
Like bah bah bah boo boo
Calling the beautiful creatures...
只有你能理解 孤苦伶仃是什么感觉
You are the one who knows what being alone and...
额 你邪恶 我狠毒 哦呵呵
Misunderstood. you are the "evil" to my "mortal".
你应该改个名字叫话唠
I can see why they call you Gabi
在哪儿呢 你这个肮脏的家禽
Where are you,you filthy fowl
站住
Hold!
我之前的行动战略不对
I've been going about this all wrong
我应该去更高的地方找
I need to search him from higher around.
哦 你刚才腾空了将近整整一秒钟
You stay there for almost full second this time.
太棒了 简直太NB了
Bravo! Bravissimo!
你看什么看 帮我上去
What you do looking at? Take me up there.
高点
Higher.
再高点
Even higher.
稍微再高点
A little bit higher.
低点 现在低点 很好 现在正好
lower lower now.Yes... perfect.
哇哦 这么一大群祸害
Ugh, it's an infestation
呵呵 继续庆祝吧 你们很快就要高兴不起来了
Keep celebrate, I'll be pooping on your party pronptly.
嗨 尼克  嗨 佩克罗
Hi, Nico. Hi, Peter.
我们来对地方了 这就是火爆 亚马逊的火爆
We have come to the right place. This is zhe pop in Amazon.
我们要把这些金刚鹦鹉带回里约
We could bring these macaws back to Rio
参加有史以来最棒的狂欢节演出 我现在灵感如泉涌
And have the best carnaval show ever. I'm inspired.
抱歉 城里来的鸟
Sorry to break it your cityboys
我看你们还是去找别的明星吧
But you'll have to find some other talent
谁也不许离开这里
nobody leaves the tribe.
哦 还有 丛林里不许留下人类的东西
And no human things in jungle.
听懂了么
Understand?
什么 他什么毛病
What's his problem?
我被扒光了...
I feel naked...
差点就能流芳百世了
We could been legends
我们已经超级无敌了 可是...你懂我的意思吗
We are already awesome, but you know what I'm saying
什么都有啊
We had all.
没被发掘的明星 好的创意
The undiscovered talent,the big idea and the inspiration
可是没有办法把他们带回里约...
but if we can not take this guys to Rio ..
就什么都没有
We got nothing.
什么都没有？
Nothing?
别那么失落嘛 不是还有我老婆吗
Hold your mangoes, we still have Eva
怎么
What?
哇哦 你跳的还是那么好 珠珠
Wow You still got zhe move, Ju-Ju
-我快累死了
- I'm so exhausted.
-是啊 我们该去休息了
-Yeah, we should get some rest
找个旅馆或者酒店
Find a local innl or B&B nearby.
你在胡说些什么啊
What is this crazy talk?
不 你们就住我家里
Now, you guys are staying in my nest
今晚我巡逻
I'm on charge tonight.
-我的家 就是你们的家
- My house is all yours.
-你真是太好了 背头
- That's really nice, Beto.
谢谢 但我觉得我们能搞定
Thank you but we're fine
再说我们一大家子 住单身公寓 挤不下
Besides our whole family couldn't possibly fit in your bachelor pad
哇哦
Wow!
这里的房价一定非常低吧
Real estate must be pretty cheap around here.
哇哦 真是不可思议
Wow...This is incredible.
你说这里?
Oh, this old nest?
这只是我最近随便弄的
It's just something I put together last minute
当然 用的是我的两只翅膀
With my own two wings, of course.
我的力气
And my strength.
还有我的肌肉（...）
And my breast.
爸爸 这里好大 有六个卧室呢
Daddy is huge It has 6 bedrooms.
-我要最大的这间
- I'll get zhe big one.
-我是最大的
- No, I'm the oldest.
就比我大3分钟外加2.5秒
Only for 3 minutes and 2.5 seconds.
我真希望有一天
I hoped to one day be blessed
我也有一群小鬼抢房间
with a bunch of little Betinhos cause my own.
-一定会的
- I think you did
-不会吧 这里还有鸟浴盆
- No way! A bird bath!
还有按摩
- And it's Jacuzzi!
嘿 布鲁 我告诉你
Blu meet you something
如果你出了任何事 任何...
If anything..I mean anything ever happen to you
我会帮忙照顾好你的家人
I'll take care of your family.
行了 睡个好觉
All right, buddy. Sleep well.
-晚安 珠珠   -晚安
- Good night, Ju-Ju. - Good night.
好了 一切都安全了
Okya all clear.
《Don't Go Away》
Jewel：月光和星光
Moonbeats and starlight
神奇的曙光
magical Twilight
最温暖的雨
The warmest rain
听他低吟你的名字
Hear it wispering your names
午夜的彩虹
Rainbows at midnight
让星空闪耀
sparkling night sky
不要远走
Don't go away
多停留一天
stay another day
你能再唱一遍吗？
Can you sing again please.
该睡觉了
Time to bad now.
多棒的一天啊
What an amazing day.
一直以来 我...
All this time, I...
我都没奢望过他们还活着
I never let myself...hope that they were alive but..
但是他们真的还都活着
But they are.
我们找到家人了 布鲁
We found our family Blu
这会改变一切的
This changes everything.
是的
Yeah.
等等 什么？ 改变什么？
Wait wait what? What changing?
珠儿
Jewel
去..去 走开
Go on
亲爱的 别 别这样 很痒的
Honey stop. That's tickles.
哈哈 真有意思
That was fun.
迪耶戈!
Tiago!
快走 迪耶戈 看我们走
Come on, Tiago! Let's go!
早上好
Good morning.
或者我应该说 下午好
Or should I say afternoon.
早上好 先生
Morning sir.
生活在这里得习惯早起
Our days in jungle is start early.
早上好 爸爸
Good morning, Daddy.
真是我的好女儿 她早就起来了
That's my girl see? already up and at'em
早上好 亲爱的
Good morning sweety.
你干嘛让我睡懒觉
Why did you let me sleep in?
你说什么呢？你每天都睡懒觉
What are you talking about? You sleep in every day.
-是的 可是...   -爸爸
- Yeah, but... - Hey Dad!
咪咪阿姨说泥土对消化有好处
Aunt Mimi said plants is good for digestion.
-试试啊   -不 宝贝儿 我刚刚刷过牙
- Try some. - No,sweety, I just brushed..
味道不错吧 我再去弄点
Is good, right? I'll go get some more.
聪明的孩子
My girl.
我说要领格鲁转一转
So I thought I'd take Stu here for a little tour of the area
参观一下
Show him around
-这主意太好了  -什么？
- It's a great idea. - What?
你跟爸爸出去转转 我带孩子们探探险
You go fan with Dad, and I'll take a explore with the kids.
-恩 好的   -你会喜欢的
- Okay, sure. - You'll love it.
恩 好的  我只要...
Okay, great. I just get a...
行了  好了
Okay  ready.
行了 布鲁 靠近点
Okay Blu come closer.
-太近了   -好的
- Not so close. - Okay.
听着...
Listen...
我看不下去了 你把人类的口袋扔掉 行吗？
I can't look at it  You gotta lose that human pocket ok?
这只是个腰包
This here is a fanny pack.
腰包嘛 很可爱
A fanny pack, amiable.
但这是人类的
Is human.
现在你已经是部落的一员了
Now that will join the tribe
你以后用不着它了
You wouldn't need it any anymore.
我们在河边泥岸上见
I'll meet you by the clay banks
哦 不 加入部落？
No, wait, join the tribe?
他不会以为我们真要搬到丛林里来吧
He does not actually think we move to the jungle, doesn't he?
不 不 他是因为我们来了 太激动了
No, he's just excitied for us here
别扫兴好么
Let's not spoil the moment ok.
再说了 不带这个腰包去又不会要了你的命
Besides, it won't kill you to leave behind the fanny pack
好吧 你赢了
All right, you win.
我不带腰包就是了
I leave the fanny pack behand.
老婆开心 日子舒心
Happy wife happy life.
再见 亲爱的 玩的开心点
Bye honey. Have fun.
哦 当然 再见
Yeah sure. Goodbye.
各位 该起床了
Guys wakey wakey
起床啦！
Wake up!
伊娃 你有角色了
Eve you got it.
那个野性亚马逊怎么样了？
What happened on Amazon untapped?
我订了计划
Here is the plan
今天面试 然后明天预演一场
Audition today and rehearse the show tomorrow.
我们？什么 你在说法语么？
We, you said we, are you speak French?
行了 赶紧的 我们开始吧
Come on cha-cha. Let's get started.
哇哦 她动作可够快的
Wow..she is being working.
准备好了就可以开始了
Anytime! When ready.
每次碰见个男的 我就想把他追到手
可是他们最后都逃走了 我就装傻 我就装酷
管他们想什么 做什么
我不关心 到此结束
(太快了，没听明白....)
-下一个  -我们是
- Next! -We are the..
神奇的巴西战舞龟
Amazing capoeiristas turtles.
太精彩了 再来一个 再来一个
Bravo! Another one! Another one!
抱歉 伙计们 刚才谁表演
Sorry guys! Did I miss something?
嗨 我叫格兰纳 我是水豚
Hi my name is Clara, the capybara
我要唱一首我最喜欢的歌
and I'll sing my favorite song.
回忆
Memory
孤零零的站在月光里
All I lonely under the moonlight
告诉我
Touch me
离开是如此的容易
is so easy to leave me
再这么吃下去我们就没有演员了
If you keep eating at there'll get no show.
这里不是比谁吃的多！
It's not your eat competition!
嘿 你飞的好快 真的好快
Oh hey, you're fast. You're really fast
我觉得我翅膀已经拉伤了
I think I pulled a wing or something
你这老鸟飞的还真快
You are really fast for a old bird.
我是说...你的智慧
For such a wise...wise
智慧 拥有很多智慧的鸟
Wise bird, a wise bird.
智慧一般是随年龄一起增长的
Wisdom is which sometimes comes with age
不过年轻的时候也增长 比如像你
But also can happen when you're young like you
又年轻 又智慧
In your case You can be wise and young
这种组合很少见 不过看到你真的好让人激动
Which is kind of a rare combination.But thrilling when it happens
-安静点儿   -哦 谢谢
- Be quiet. - Thank you, sir.
你应该把城市的习惯丢掉了
It's time to take the city of you.
你要学习基本的...丛林生存要素
Need to learn the basics of jungle survival
我们不是出来观光的吗？
I thought we were to go sightseeing
今天是训练日
It's training day.
来吧 泥土是你的朋友
Come on! Mud is your friend.
这是你的伪装 感觉他 品尝他
She is their camouflage. Feel it, Taste it.
如果没感觉 说明你的动作不对
You don't feel tasty, you not doing
你不会想被人类看见的
You don't want to be seen by humans.
快点儿 你是蓝皮克斯鹦鹉还是火鸡？
Come on Are you a macaw or turkey?
快点 再快点
Faster! Faster!
加油！你不想被吃掉吧
Come on! You don't want to be eaten.
你独自一人在丛林里
You're alone in jungle.
你被陷阱抓住了
You get caught in trap.
你会怎么办？
What will you do?
-如果我的腰包在的话  -不
Well, if I had my fanny pack... -no
-你要用你的嘴   -我的嘴？
- Uses your beak! - My beak!
这是你最重要的工具
Your most important tool.
好的 我用我的嘴
Okay, I use my beak.
-就差一点了   -时间到
- Almost. - Time's up.
你挂了
You are jaguar's meat.
罗伯特第一次就成功了
Roberto got first tried.
肯定的
Of course he did.
上 上 盘旋
Up, Up, plane!
现在倒着飞
Now Back!
倒飞？什么 不 只有蜂鸟能倒着飞
Fly back? Only hummingbird can fly backward.
倒着飞
Backward.
跳 飞起来 俯冲 在高点
Under! Over! Under! Over!
-干得好   -谢谢
- Good job! - Thanks.
没说你
Not you
这是巴西栗树
Brazil nut trees
这些树对我们的生存至关重要
These trees are the key to our alive
这些树为我们提供食物 它们供养我们
The trees feed us they sustain us
他们...
They...
醒醒
Wake up!
我醒着 我醒着呢 栗巴西还是..
I'm up...! Em..nut brazil..
哦 不 巴西栗树什么的 哦 明白了
Brazil nut trees something...got it
这很重要
This is important.
我们要保护这些树
We have to protect these trees.
我们的未来要依靠他们
Our future depends on it.
嗨 艾迪 这跟班是谁啊
Edie, who's that sidekick?
你现在需要护士了？
You get a nurses now?
-嗨 我是...   -你们是不是
- Hi, I'm... - - Aren't you boys
离我们的地盘太近了？
get a little bit too close to our side?
我们说好的 费利佩
We have an deal, Felipe.
嘿 别紧张 你知道我们对你满怀深情
Relax! You know you got a old man love for you
来吧 伙计们快飞吧
Come on boys  let's fly
给天空添些色彩吧 让他们去哭鼻子咯
paint the skies  before they start to cry.
-他们挺和气的   -树林那边是他们的
-They seem nice. - They have their side
这边是我们的
and we have ours.
最近食物短缺
The food is scarce.
从没看见他们离我们的家园这么近
I've never seen them so close to the village before.
-别让他们看到你   -哦 对 抱歉
- Do not let them see you. - Right right sorry.
也许我们应该去找琳达
Maybe we should go find Linda.
-那是什么？  -琳达是人
- What is Linda? - Linda is the person...
-她把我养大   -什么？
- who created me. - What?
-你是宠物？  -不 不..
-You're the pet? -No no I mean..
不是你想的那样 我们是朋友
Is not what you think, I was a companion.
什么？朋友 噢..
You like it? Oh..
难怪你这幅样子
That explains everything.
-琳达是我的家人  -家人？
- Linda's family. - Family?
人类不是我们的家人
Humans aren't family.
你没明白 他们是来帮忙的
You do not understand, they coming here to help.
听我说 绝对不能带人类来我们的部落
Listen to me, we do not bring human into the tribe.
远离人类我们才活到现在
That is only reason we still alive.
这你总应该明白吧
You can't be confused about this
你明白了吗？
Understand?
是的 明白
Yeah. Got it.
现在 观光结束
Sightseeing is over.
你看见鸟巢了嚒？
Did you see the nest?
图里奥 你没事吧？
Tulio are you okay?
我没事 我很好 我...
Yes, I'm fine i'm ok...
我不太好
I'm not ok.
图里奥 他们在砍伐森林
Tulio they're Cutting down the forest!
-琳达你要去哪？  -去和他们说
- Where is it going? - To talk to them.
你去跟鸟说 我去和人说
You talk to birds and I talk to humans.
不 等等
No wait!
嘿 先生 你好
Hi hi mister hello
我命令你把电锯关掉
You can take it easy with that chain saw.
有很珍贵的鸟类居住在这片丛林里
There are rare birds living around here.
你不能把这些树都砍掉
You can not cut these trees!
哦 亲爱的 你在这儿啊
Oh sweetheart, there you are
我到处找你
I was looking for you.
嗨 你好 这儿真漂亮 对吗？
Hello! It's beautiful out here, isn't it?
你们迷路了？
You two lost?
迷路？ 没有 呵呵 迷路？
Lost? Not!
我们是来 来 来度蜜月的
We are here.. have honeymoon.
我们正要回去和旅行团汇合呢
We're actually just heading back to join the tour
今天晚上 有一场卡拉ok
Is a karaoke night.
走吧 亲爱的 人家还等着我们去唱..月亮河呢
Come on henny, moonriver isn't going sing a song.
琳达 这些人砍得可不止这些树
Linda, woods aren't the only things these guys cut.
快跑 琳达 我拖住他们 快跑！
Run! Run Linda I'll hold them off. Go! Go!
请让一下
Excuse me
来吧 我们来比赛
Come on! Let's Race.
-真是太棒了  -好样的 迪耶戈
- Cool! - All right, Tiago.
迪耶戈
Tiago!
哦 太爽了
Oh that's so good
嘿 你们回来啦
Hey you're back
玩儿的怎么样啊？
How did it go?
我们玩的很开心 今天很有教育意义
We had a great time. It was educational.
爸爸 鲍勃叔叔教了我一些很酷的飞行技巧
Dad, Uncle Beto taught me some cool fly tricks.
-叔叔？  -看 我会倒着飞啦
- Uncle? - Look, I can fly backwards.
是啊 你很有天分
Yeah you are naturel tree bird.
丛林的生活技巧要从小学起
It's Never too soon to learn the way in jungle Tiago.
可是有些家伙学不会
Also someone may never learn.
我要去..洗个澡（可怜的blu）
I'm getting go have a.. clean up.
罗伯特 我看见人类在丛林附近
Roberto we saw human near the orchard.
你要保持警惕
I mean you have to stay aleart.
丛林的生活方法..
Way lives in jungle...
我倒想学离开的方法
I'd better learen go out of the jungle.
哦 他在那儿 我们的机会来啦
There he is. Now is our chance.
哦 我真是太激动了
I'm so excitied!
准备舌头弹弓
Prepare the tongue-a-bult.
查理 让我重新飞起来
Charlie, make me fly again.
去干掉他们 老虎
Get them tiger.
快向征服你的凤头鹦鹉跪拜吧
Bow before the conquering cockatoo!
你是不是有病啊 伙计？
What is your problem, dude?
天哪 好变态啊
That was sick!
我说 面试的时候就该有这种镜头
That's the energy you bring to an audition
面试？
Audition?
是啊 我就是面试的 我有一个很棒的....
Yeah,thats actually why I'm here.I've got a greatlittle...
您继续
go on.
我们在寻找一个新的明星
We are looking for a new star.
明星？
Star?
你看上去很眼熟
You look familiar.
我们是不是哪儿见过？
Don't I know you from somewhere?
不 不 不会的
No, I don't think so
我叫...鲍勃
I am... Bob.
小鲍勃..
Yes Bob the bird..
无所谓啦 展示才艺吧
OK. show us what you got
恩 一开始我很害怕
At first, I was afraid
我惊得目瞪口呆
I was petrified.
我一直以为我没法再活下去
I kept thinking that I could never live
没法再展翅飞翔
I could barely fly.
我在无数个慢慢长夜里回想
And I spend oh.. so many nights thinking
回想起他对我的残忍
how he did me wrong
于是我变得坚强
But I grew strong.
我学会了如何随遇而安
And I learned how to get alone
走吧 快滚
Go on, now go
《I Will Survive》
滚出这扇门
Walk out the door
转身离开吧
Just turn around now
现在这里是我的了
It's I who have the floor
你不就是那个想用分手来伤害我的人吗？
was not you who tried hurt me with goodbye
-你以为我会垮掉  -哦 不
Did you think I'd lay down and die
你以为我会躺在这儿死掉？
-不 奈杰尔你不会  -我会活下来
-Oh, no Nige  -I'll survive
只要我知道怎么去恨 我就会活下来
As long as I know how to hate, I know I'll stay alive ahh..
我会好好过这一生
I've got all my life to live
我又满腔的爱要付出
And I got all my love to give
-我会活下来  -你会活下来
-And I'll survive -You'll survive
-我会活下来  -我们会活下来
-And I'll survive  -We'll survive
我是个幸存者 我的眼睛虎视眈眈
I'm a survivor, I've got the eye of a tiger
加强修炼 多吃高纤
I've been training again and eating my fiber
你只是活着 而我是鲜活的活着
You've been staying alive well I've been staying aliverer
你要坐稳了 我吐口水的时候声音响彻云霄
Watch where you sit when I spit my saliva like boom
你从来没见过一只凤头鹦鹉
You've never seen a cockatoo
随着摇滚的节奏 又唱又跳 尽情摇摆
Rocking shaking and droping and opoing and locking too
看看我的本事 都用不着调音器
Watch what I can do without no autotune
怎么样
Say what?
真的没有用哦
All he did it
如果你你打压我
If you try to keep me down
只会让我变得更坚强
I'll just come back stronger
你想打断我
If you try to cut me short
只会让我说的更多
I'll just come back longer
如果你想用乒乓球打败我
If you beat me at ping pong
我会变成乒乓球健将
I'll ust play ping pong-er
给我个王位 我准备好上位
Give my my throne, I'm ready to thrive
我很清楚 我会活下去
I know I'll survive
我会...
I will...
活下去
Survive
谢谢 我是小鸟 鲍勃
Yeah Thank you, I am little Bob the bird
他真是太帅了
He is so hot.
-好了 就是他 我要了
- Yes that's it you're in
-虽然不如伊娃 但是你很棒
- You is not Eve,  but you're awesum.
明天晚上狂欢节演出的时候见
We'll see you at the performance tomorrow night
这里所有的鸟都会来看
Everyone from this village is coming
你一定会红到发紫的
It's gonna be off the charts
所有鸟
Everyone.
Everyone?
这是个完美的计划
Is the perfect plan.
算你运气好 拔你几根刺 豪猪
Bless the godden plating you, porcupine.
滚吧
Go away.
与其满林子追那只鸟
In stead of chasing that bird all over the jungle
不如让他演出的时候自己送上门
We let him come to us at the Carnaval show
我会在舞台上迷住他们
I'll mesmerize them from te stage
而在观众席里 你 我的小噶比...
While in the audience you my little Gabi
你会成为我的 迷你致命武器
You'll be my petite weapon of muss destruction
这场演出将会是..
It will be a performance..
好看到死
To die for
只有我才笑得出那种气场
It only works when I do it.
好的 爱你哦
Okay. Love you.
啊...舒服
So minty.
好耶
Yes!
哦 亲爱的 你在这儿 怎么这么长时间？
Hi, sweetheart. here you are. Why is it taking so long?
啊 别再弄那个GPS了
Enough with this GPS, seriously!
我们一起去看日落 快走吧
Whole tribe is gathering for sunset come on
等一下 我刚找到琳达和图里奥的坐标
Hey wait. I just find Linda and Tulio's coordinates.
他们就在林子的另一半 瞧
They're just on the other side of the orchard, look!
他们离得很近
They are very close.
是呀 我知道你爸爸不相信人类
I know that your father does not totally trust humans
可他一旦见到了 他就会改变想法
But I'm sure he met them he change his mind
琳达他们能保护这里
They can help to keep this place safe.
是的 布鲁 我爸自己能解决
Yeah Blu, my dad is doing and...
我说你能不能忘掉琳达和图里奥一会儿？
Can't you just forget your Linda and tulio one minute?
好好享受日落？
and enjoy the sunset?
但是这不是我们的计划吗？
But I thought that was our plan.
GPS:路线规划完成
New gide is complete
恩...我...你知道
I. ..You know...
有些地方也许不该被发现
Maybe some places should't be found.
也许就应该与世隔绝
Maybe they should be left alone.
她吃了一只虫子 一只虫子
She ate a bug! A bug!
布鲁 布鲁 冷静
Blu blu bul...calm down!
冷静？我们有个计划
Calm down? We have a plan
帮助琳达和图里奥找到鹦鹉 然后回家
Help Linda and Tulio find the flocks and get home.
可是我提醒他 她根本就不理我
But I mentioned her she completely shut me down
哦 还有他的爸爸
Oh..And her father..
他就是个疯子 他对人类的看法很奇怪
Totally a nut job. Has a weird thing about humans.
他对人类的看法很奇怪
He's got this weird thing about humans
他爱人类 他是个宠物
He loves them! He is a pet!
宠物？
A pet?
他叫我宠物！
He called me a pet!
真不敢相信 他居然当我的面这么说
I can't believe he used that word to my face
像是把我当成敌人似的
It's looks like me as the enemys or something!
他跟我们不是一路的 你要盯着点儿他
It is not one of us, Roberto. Keep eyes on him.
还有那个罗伯特 他在监视
And that Roberto He is always watching.
总是在珠儿身边转 总是唱着什么歌
He's always hovering around Jewel He is always singing something
我根本比不上他
I can't compete with that.
你要拿出点鸟样来 从被驯养的状态中解放出来
You have to be a bird guy! If release of domestication!
用珠儿的眼光看这里
Try to see this place through her eyes.
去尝尝珠儿品尝的那些味道
Taste the flavors she's tasting.
让我去吃虫子？
So..I should eat a bug?
想想都觉得恶心 在考虑下吧
This is disgusting think about it.
-闪光片 我的闪光片在哪儿？
- Shine! Where is my glitter?
-哦 对不起 对不起
- Oh Sorry, sorry
我不需要听道歉 我要闪光片
I don't want apologize I want glitter
充满魔力的表演最终要靠的就是闪光片
Brightness is absolutely essential for magic performances.
你怎么就不懂呢？
Do not you know anything?
伙计们 快去彩排 明天是个大日子
Guys, rehearsal... big day tomorrow
想起来了吗？ 来吧 你来吗 爸爸？
Remember about? Come on! You're coming right Dad?
哦 当然了
Oh Yes... of course.
那孩子把娱乐搞得像是交作业
That girl puts the business in show business
-布鲁 记住   -我知道 我知道了
- Remember... - I know I know
老婆开心 日子舒心
Happy wife happy life.
多么美好的晨曦啊！
What a glorious morning!
我都忘记了能够享受这样的早晨
I forgot I could have a mornings like this.
你最爱吃的
Your favorite.
哦..你记得这个 这真是太好了
Ao..You remember. Isn't that nice
这感觉真是好极了 谢谢你 布鲁
It's so crazy good. Thank you so much Blu.
对呀
That's it!
我要给珠儿一个惊喜 给他送早餐 马上就来
I'll be the one to surprise her breakfast in bed coming up
巴西栗 你们在哪儿？
Brazil nuts, where are you?
我就知道你们在这附近
I know you around here somewhere.
不 快回来 等等
No hey hey come back here
-那不是玩具  -GPS:违章驾驶 靠边停车
- This is not a toy! - Directing dangerous
不 不 不要
No no don't do it.
抓到你了
Gotcha!
总算找到了 巴西栗
Finally! Brazil nuts!
这个才是我最重要的工具
This is my most important tool.
好啊 好啊 瞧瞧这是谁来了
Well well well what do we have here
看样子不是所有的鸟都遵守老艾迪的规矩
I guess the old Eddie's rules don't apply to everyone
这儿是我们的地盘
You are in our side.
哦 是吗？ 对不起 我没注意到 真抱歉
Really? My bad. Do not know that, sorry.
对不起 对不起
Sorry, sorry.
闯进我们的地盘 抢我们的食物
You come over here, take our food
现在你还侮辱我？
and now you insult me?
不 不 不 这件事儿完全是个误会
No, no. This is just a big misunderstanding
知道吗 我非常想接受你的道歉
You know, I wish I could accept your apology
你看上去像是只好鸟
You seem like a nice bird
可是这代表战争！
but this means war!
什么？有必要吗？能代表点别的吗？
What? Does it have to? Can't it mean something else?
今天 在死亡坑
Today in the pit of doom
对不起 死亡坑 真的吗？
Sorry, the pit of doom really?
-哦 真的 -正午
- Oh,really  -highnoon.
我要腾出点地方
I'll make some room
像扫帚一样把你扫出这片林子
Sweep you up like a broom
-你干了什么？   -那是个意外
- You did what? - It was an accident.
-意外  -嘿 出了什么事？
-An accident? - What's going on?
多谢布鲁 我们可能要失去这片林子了
Thanks to Stu here,we're going  rights to the rntire grove
我只是想去摘个坚果  就一个
I was just trying to get a nut! One nut
你都不喜欢吃坚果 这到底是怎么一回事 布鲁？
You don't even like nuts,what's gotten in to you Blu?
我想给你准备点早餐
I want getting it for you
哦 真的吗？
Are you were?
罗伯特 你带上最棒的鸟去
Roberto, I want your best birds on it.
我们绝不能不战而降
We will not give up without a fight!
明白
Got it!
你 别管这事儿了 净添麻烦
You! Stay out of it! Have kitted enough.
-等等   -布鲁 他是对的
- Wait! - Blu, he's right.
就让爸爸和罗伯特去处理这件事吧
Maybe you should let dad and Roberto handle it
-你也觉得我处理不了？
- You don't think I can do this?
-不 我只是...
- Not! I just...
只是不太确定 外交在不在你的专长范围内
Do not know if it's your exactly in expertise
快走  快走 死亡坑
Let's go... pit of doom now!
无线电！
Radio
我希望你别介意 我把这儿当自己家
I hope you do not mind  I make myself at home
棒棒糖？
A lollipop?
真是可惜啊 你们两位大老远跑来保护这片森林
Is a shame. You all came this way to protect the jungle.
我们看看它会不会报答你们
Let's see if she returns the favor.
两个疯子...
Tree huggers...
-罗伯特   -费利佩
- Roberto... - Felipe...
给他点厉害瞧瞧
No mercy!
-我得阻止他们  -什么 布鲁？
- I have to stop this. - What? Blu!
停下 停下 艾迪 这太疯狂
Stop, stop! Edwardo this is crazy.
我们是高等物种
We are intelligent species
我们能更好的解决问题
with advanced problem solving techniques.
这是你挑起来的 等着瞧吧
You brought this on us! Now watch.
- 头冲上  -尾巴冲上
- Head. - Tails.
我讨厌这工作
I hate this job.
-这是比赛？ 这是比赛！
- Oh, it's a game! it's a game!
-这不是比赛 这是战争
- It's not a game It's war.
嘿 嘿 嘿 今天死亡坑天气不错
It's a beautiful day in the pit of doom!
-这是胜者为王的比赛  -七局四胜
- It's winner take all! - It's the best of seven.
获胜者将得到整片巴西栗子林
The winner will take control of the entire Brazil nut grove.
这就像足球 这我会玩
It's just like soccer. I can do this.
有什么特别的战术吗？4-4-2 还是 5-4-1
All right. Any special strategies? Will we be running at 4-4-2 or 5-4-1?
怎么踢 教练 我踢什么位置
What are we doing here, coach? What position is likely?
事实上我给你准备了一个合适的位置
Actually I do have a perfect spot for you.
水 这儿有水 来喝水吧
Water. Water here. Get your water.
好的 谢谢
Okay, thanks.
罗伯特 他所向披靡势不可挡 到处都是他的身影
Roberto is unstoppable! He's incredible!
-加油罗伯特  -哼 这我也能行
- Go, Roberto! - I could have done that.
罗伯特和对手保持距离 他正在向前冲 向前冲
Roberto's breaking! There he go!There he go!
他射门了！
He shooted!
进啦！
Goal!
哦 费利佩抢到了球 红金刚鹦鹉要扭转局面
Felipe has the ball! The red macaws are making a comeback!
费利佩传给提科 提科传给马里奥
Felipe pass to Tito, Tito to Mario.
马里奥传给凯撒 凯撒传给安东尼
Mario to Keita, Keita to Antonio.
安东尼射门得分！
It's goal!
嘿 去你的吧
Yes! In your face!
费利佩 罗伯特 费利佩 罗伯特...
Felipe, Roberto, Roberto, Felipe, Felipe...
射门
Goal!
-这一定很疼  -上 上
- I guess this is gonna hurt. - Go go!
费利佩 利佩 利佩
Felipe! Lipe, Lipe, Lipe!
-犯规   -嘿 得了吧 裁判
-Foul   -Come on Referee
-好吧 你上  -真的？
- Okay. You are in. - Really?
没说你 你
Not you. You!
学着点吧 送水小子
Watch and learn waterboy!
-好吧  你..你上吧  -好的
- All right. Get in there. - Yes!
开始吧 教练
Here, here we go.
嘿 爸爸
Yeah, Dad!
现在有位替补队员上场了 他会是秘密武器吗？
A new player is coming off the bench! Is he a secret weapon?
他不就是那个送水的吗
I think he's the waterboy.
没人防我  没人防我 把球传给我啊
Hey! I'm open! I'm open! Toss it to me!
传给我 我这儿没人防守 快传给我啊
Pass to me! I'm open. I am wide open!
把球传给我
Pass the ball to me!
-谢谢你把球传给我
- Thanks for the pass, Blu!
-借用一下
- Might I borrow this?
罗伯特向前挺进 他避开一个防守 又避开一个
Roberto looked this. He shied a defense, another!
罗伯特 进啦
Roberto! Goal!
目前的比分 3比3
We are tie now at the pit of doom.
接下来谁先进球 谁就赢得比赛
Whoever scores next... - Wins all!
我来接 我来接
Oh! I got it, I got it!
加油 布鲁
Come on, Blu.
哇噢 送水小子突然表现出了专业水准
Wow! The water boy suddenly playing like a pro!
把球传给罗伯特
Pass the ball to Roberto!
快传球  快传球！
Pass the ball! Pass the ball!
-布鲁 等等  -我自己能搞定
- Blu, wait! - This bird's gonna covered!
看上去这个秘密武器 突然走火了
It looks like the secret weapon lost its fire.
我们来看看艾迪现在的反应
Let's go to Edwardo for his reaction.
我要杀了这只该死的宠物
I'm gonna kill you fanny pack!
哦 老艾迪
Check it out, old Eddie.
看样子你们没有坚果吃了 只能减肥了
Looks like you guys are gonna have to start a nut-free diet!
这场比赛在我们那儿会传为佳话的
We'll be talking about that for a long time.
我真不该对人类的宠物报抱什么希望
I should have never expected more of a human's pet.
嘿 刚才你怎么回事儿啊？
What happened back there?
我太想融入这个大家庭了
I was trying to be one of the tribe.
但我可能永远都不能成为你爸爸希望的那样
But I guess I'm never gonna be the bird like your dad wants me to be.
-你..说什么？   -我想我们该回家了
- My... what? - I think it's time to go home.
-我正要跟你说呢   -跟我说什么？
- We should talk about this. - Talk about what?
布鲁 看看周围
Blu, look around.
孩子们这里 在野外玩的这么的开心
The kids are thriving. They love being in the wild.
也许这里就是我们的家
Maybe this place is home.
我们的家？ 这里是我们的家？
Home? How can this be home?
我尽全力适应这里 帮助他们
I've done everything I can to fit in and help out
可我做什么都不对
but no matter what I do it's wrong!
这不是我们的家 珠儿
That's not home, Jewel.
也许属于你 但不是我的
Maybe for you, but not for me.
知道吗？ 你应该清楚你到底需要什么
You know what? You need to figure out what you want.
而且
And maybe
别老想着你自己 也为我们想想吧
Stop thinking about just yourself and start thinking about us.
出发 出发 快点
Move out! Let's go.
太好了
Beautiful.
琳达 图里奥
Linda! Tulio!
再见 琳达
Goodbye  Linda.
-再见 小腰包
- Goodbye, fanny pack
请在能拐弯的时候拐弯
Turn around when possible.
抱歉 GPS小姐 不是你的错 是我的不对
Sorry, GPS lady. It's not you it's...it's me.
再见 煎饼 再见 咖啡
Goodbye, pancakes. Goodbye, coffee.
再见 咖啡
Goodbye coffee.
琳达？
Linda?
琳达
Linda!
艾迪说的对  你是个叛徒
Edwardo was right! Traitor!
-等等 你不明白？
- Wait. You don't understand.
-我有什么不明白的 与人类为伍？
- What don't I understand? Siding with humans?
-你对人类了解多少？
- What do you even know about humans?
-哦 我很了解他们
- Oh I know everything.
他们引诱你 把你抓起来
They lure you in! They trap you!
他们还给你洗脑！
They destroy your mind!
鹦鹉要吃饼干吗 要吃饼干吗？
Polly want a cracker? Polly want a cracker?
不 我受够饼干了 我讨厌饼干
No! Enough crackers! I hate crackers.
-快走 罗伯特
- Come on, Roberto!
-是他们 是他们 是他们！
- It's them! It's them! It's them!
让开
Roberto, get out of there!
不要 不要 我不要饼干
Not again, not again! No more crackers!
你冷静点
Stop out of it!
听好 我们还有个机会阻止这一切
Look, we got one chance to stop this, okay?
我去找到我的朋友
I have to find my friends.
你飞回去警告大家 明光吗？
You fly back and warn the others, you got it?
-明白   -好的 快去！
- Yeah, I got it. - Okay! Go! - Okay!
人类 人类！
Humans! Humans!
-往你的左边 不右边 右边  -左还是右？
- Your left! Right! - Left or right?
你的右腿 我的左腿
Your right leg my left leg.
好的 就这样
- Good good.
现在..往上爬  爬!
Now go..up up.
差一点了 就快到了
Reach. Almost there!
琳达 我真的很抱歉
Linda I'm so sorry.
虽然情况很糟糕 但是我全世界哪儿也不想去
As bad as this is, there is no place...
只想和你在一起
I would rather be in the whole world than with you
哪怕是被拴在一棵树上 (记得 第一部里Jewel和blu吗?)
Even it's tie to a tree
哦 琳达~
oh Linda
布鲁 布鲁
Blu! Blu!
-琳达？   -下面！
- Linda? - Down here!
-啊 布鲁  -你怎么在这儿？
- What? Blu! - What are you doing here?
这里很危险
This is dangerous.
真难以置信 里约飞到这儿有2000英里
That's incredible! It's a 2000-mile flight!
-我们跟着他  -太神奇了
Let's follow him!
我就说我听到他的声音了
I told you I heard him!
还给我钥匙
blu: Let me take those.
ps：好有Avatar的感觉
一切都完了 人类 人类
It's over! Humans! The light! The light!
那些光 那些光 不...
The light...No...
自从我们找到他 他就不停的说胡话
He's been staggering like this since we found him.
伐木工来了 布鲁和他们在一起
The loggers are coming and Blu is with them.
-他是个叛徒
- Traitor!s.
-不 布鲁是想帮我们
- No, Blu is trying to help us.
什么？ 就他自己？  -我们快撤
- What? By himself? - Let's evacuate!
离开这里 所有的鸟立刻出发 快 快 快
We are leaving. Let's go, everyone move out! Go! Go! Go!
爸爸 这次不行 我不能和你一起走
Dad, no, not this time. I'm not going with you.
你必须和我一起走
You have to go with me
我不能再让家人面临危险
I will not put my family in danger again.
布鲁也是我的家人 我不会丢下他的
Blu is my family and I'm not leaving him behind.
不用担心
You don't have to.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
听着 埃德沃德 也许我不是这里最有鸟样的鸟
Look, Edwardo, I might not be the birdiest bird in the flock.
就现在来说 这是好事
But for once that's actually a good thing.
你了解丛林 我了解人类
You know the jungle, I know humans.
我们合作就能阻止伐木工
And I know that together we can stop them.
不能让他们夺走我们的家园
We can't let them take our home.
虽然这里又热又吵 到处是恐怖的虫子
Sure it's hot, and loud and filled of creepy bugs.
可这是属于我们的 我们要为他而战
But it's ours. Let's fight for it!
-谁跟我去？  -我跟你...
- Who is with me? - I'm with you!
还有谁吗？
Anybody else?
停下 停下
Stop! Stop! Stop!
停下！
Stop!
哦 这就对了 请尊重热带雨林
Oh yeah! Respect the rainforest!
我就知道  我就知道 我就...
I knew it! I knew it! I knew...
你这是要去哪儿？
Where do you think you're going?
那只不过是一群该死的鸽子
It's just a bunch of pigeons.
给我回去干活
Get back to work!
你带头 布鲁
Lead the way  Blu.
终于叫对了 你叫我布鲁
That's my name, yes. You called me Blu!
对 我叫布鲁！
Yes! I am Blu.
哦 哦 对 有蓝色羽毛的鸟
What? Oh, oh, right. Birds of blue feathers...
团结在一起
have to stick together!
准备好了吗？ 现在往下
Everybody ready? And under!
往上
Over!
倒飞！
Backwards!
我会活下去 我会活下去
I'll survive, I will survive.
-抓到了   -哇 好准
- Got it! - Wow, precise.
我才不怕什么鸟呢
I'm afraid of no birds.
进攻
Attack!
-亚马逊保卫战开始了
- It's on in the Amazon.
-准备 扔
- All right, hit it!
击掌
High-five!
-为什么？为什么？   -给我振作起来
- Why? Why? - Get hold of youelf!
炮弹来了
Incoming!
停下 他在那儿 查理 给我准备鼻射炮
There he is. Charlie, prepare the nozooka!
-迪耶戈   -这才对嘛
- Tiago. - That's what I were talking.
准备 瞄准 开火
Ready, aim, fire!
又失手了
Foiled again.
-干得好 迪耶戈  -我们是最棒的团队
- Good job, Tiago! - We are great team, Dad!
-费利佩? -你以为我会错过这个机会？
- Felipe? - You think I'd miss this party?
比赛开始
Game on!
嘿 快回来 一群饭桶 没用的东西
Hey! Come back! You are useless! All of you!
小心
Look out!
要打架 找个个子和你一样大的
Pick on someone your own size!
-不 不  -接住你了 接住你了
- No! No! - Gotcha, gotcha.
别害怕 没事了 你安全了
It's Okay, it's okay, you are safe now.
那就是琳达
That's a Linda.
还是这么默契 布鲁
We stil got it, Blu.
真是的 什么事都得我亲自干
I have to do everything myself.
-给我滚开
- Hey! Get away from that!
-不 没有人可以抢我的戏
- No way, no one steals my scene.
棒棒糖？
Lollipop?
什么？
What?
你在干嘛？ 快走 快逃命吧
What are you doing? Let go, save yourself.
-快放开  -我就不
- Come on, let go. - Never.
你疯了吗？ 你会把我们两个都害死的
Are you crazy? You are bringing both of us down! Let go!
-飞呀 似曾相识吧 布鲁  -奈杰尔
- Deja vu, Blu. - Nigel!
-布鲁  -奈杰
- Blu!  - Nigel!
你
You!
你要为你的罪恶付出最惨痛的代价
You'll pay it, pay the price for your insolence!
住手 别过来
Stop it. Get away from here.
用我愤怒的羽毛 扇肿你的脸
Give my furious feathers in your face.
-你没必要 没必要这么做
- You don't have to do this.
-我就是想这么做
- Oh, I just want to.
哦天哪 查理 机会来了
Oh my God! Charlie! This is it, this is it!
稳住 稳住
Steady, steady.
扇耳光比赛
Slap fight!
就是现在 发射！
Shoot! Shoot!
哦 奈杰尔
Oh! Nigel!
我就要死了吗？
Is this the end?
我太年轻 又太英俊 天妒英才
I was too young, too beautiful to live.
-鲍勃  -等下 那不是鲍勃
- Bob? - Hold up, that ain't Bob!
我就说我见过他
I told you I knew him from somewhere.
这是我最后的谢幕
My final curtain call
现在只剩下站票了
has standing room only.
再见
Goodbye.
不！！我干了些什么啊
No! No! What have I done?
如果不能与汝同生 那我不如死了算了
If you can not live it with me then I shall not live it at all.
那只青蛙它没有毒
That frog is not poisonous.
-什么？  -我们没有死？
- What? - We're not dead?
这个品种经常被搞错
It's a very common mistake.
它是只假的箭毒蛙
But she's a colostethus Dendrobate.
从它粉色的斑点就能看出来
You can tell by the pink spots.
可我父母从小告诉我说 我有剧毒
But my parents always told me I was poisonous
叫我别碰任何人
and shouldn't touch anyone.
你是你爹妈充话费送的吧？
You just have really mean parents.
那么现在 我们可以在一起啦
So now...We can be together!
-奈杰尔 奈杰尔 我的维克多  -谁来救救我
- Nigel! Nigel! - No! No! My victory help me!
-我绝对不会放你走的  -不 不 我会学好的
- I will never let you go! - I'm sorry, I'll be nicer.
不 不 查理
No! No! Charlie!
查理
Charlie!
这是违反自然法则的
This is unatural!
嘿 伙计们 嗨 头发没弄脏吧
Hi, guys， hi. There's nothing in my hair, right?
我们从亚马逊的腹地
Directly from the heart of the Amazon rainforest
为你带来特大新闻
we have some breaking news.
多亏了图里奥博士和他的团队
Thanks to Dr. Monteiro and his team
这里的整片区域都将会制定为
the entire area will be designated
国家野生鸟类保护区
as a national wildlife refuge
我们大家会一起确保这里的安全
and together we will make sure this place stay safe.
对吗 布鲁？
Right, Blu?
好消息还不止这一个
But that's not the only good news.
我们在丛林深处找到这只凤头鹦鹉
We found this cockatoo deep in the Amazon
他好像和一只树蛙黏在一起
and he seems to have bounded to a tree frog
我们会把它带回里约
We are bringing them back to Rio
进行持续的观察
for continuing observation.
哦 奈杰尔 我们要去里约度蜜月啦
Oh, Nigel, wow! A honeymoon in Rio!
大家一起来 拍手 拍手 摇尾巴
Put paws, downs, and tails together
这是丛林里有史以来最强大的明星阵容
for the most amazing talents ever gathered in one jungle!
下面请看--野性亚马逊
It's Amazon untamed!
《 Batucada Familia》
嘿 嘿 别咬我 别咬我
What's up? Don't Bite it. What's up? Don't Bite it
我的鸟儿朋友们
Where are my birds up?
翅膀挥舞起来
Flap your wings.
亚马逊
Amazon.
这是我们最爱的绿宝石
It's an emerald we treasure
从密林来到你的面前
Coming from the jungle to you
拍打的是心跳的节奏
Beating like it's hopping.
演绎的是自由的音符
Interpretation of the freely notes
这是我们最爱的绿宝石
It's the emerald we treasure
来自我们生活的地方
- Coming from the place where we live. - Place where we live.
充满着自由和欢乐
...happy night
时光不停飞逝
Time Flies Past as the breeze
丛林就像一阵清风 一个奇迹
快穿上舞裙 随时有人叫你跳舞
(还是没听清..)
你好 亚马逊
Hello  Amazon!
-嘿 路易兹   -嘿 小鸟们 我来了
- Luiz! - Hey birds, I made it!
欢迎来到丛林
Welcome to the Amazon!
硬汉乌龟
唱吧 宝贝儿
Sing it baby.
你确定要在亚马逊安家吗？
Are you sure you can make the Amazon our home?
-这里有热又有恐怖的虫子  -开什么玩笑
- With the heat, the creepy bugs? - What, are you kidding?
我可是丛林先生 充满野性而且还很有鸟样
I'm Mr.jungle totally wild and very birdy.
夏天还是去里约避暑吧
Maybe we can beat summer in Rio.
你是我的唯一 珠儿
You are my one of my only Jewel.
噢...
Ao...
---时间轴：张咏轩 新浪微博：@张咏轩---
结束了吗？
That's the end?
《Rio Rio (feat. B.o.B)》